A Guide to the Luther Porter Jackson Papers, 1772-1960
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- SERIES V. MATERIAL RELATING TO THE DEATH OF LUTHER JACKSON
  - Correspondence April 13, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1368)
  - Correspondence April 14, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1369)
  - Correspondence April 14, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1370)
  - Correspondence April 14, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1371)
  - Correspondence April 15, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1372)
  - Correspondence April 16, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1373)
  - Correspondence April 17, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1374)
  - Correspondence April 18, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1375)
  - Correspondence April 19, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1376)
  - Correspondence April 20, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1377)
  - Correspondence April 23, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1378)
  - Correspondence April 26, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1379)
  - Correspondence April 27, 30, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1380)
  - Correspondence May 2, 9, 1950 (Box-folder 49:1381)
  - Telegrams April 13, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1382)
  - Telegrams April 14, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1383)
  - Telegrams April 14, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1384)
  - Telegrams April 15, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1385)
  - Telegrams April 15, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1386)
  - Telegrams April 16, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1387)
  - Telegrams April 17, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1388)
  - Telegrams April 17, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1389)
  - Telegrams April 18, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1390)
  - Telegrams April 19, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1391)
  - Telegrams n.d. (Box-folder 50:1392)
  - Telegrams n.d. (Box-folder 50:1393)
  - Memorial Dinner Program n.d. (Box-folder 50:1394)
  - H.S. Dedication April 17,1955 (Box-folder 50:1395)
  - Funeral Services n.d. (Box-folder 50:1396)
  - Morning Services April 20, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1397)
  - Baccalaureate Services, L.P.S.H. School n.d. (Box-folder 50:1398)
  - Dinner Program April 27, 1952 (Box-folder 50:1399)
  - Dinner Program Feb 21, 1952 (Box-folder 50:1400)
  - Annual Dinner Program April 18, 1955 (Box-folder 50:1401)
  - Hurley, P. May 15, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1402)
  - Young, D. June 23, 1951 (Box-folder 50:1403)
  - Fleming, J. Aug 15, 1950 (Box-folder 50:1404)
  - Memoriam n.d. (Box-folder 50:1405)
  - Memoriam Statement n.d. (Box-folder 50:1406)
- SERIES VI. RESEARCH DATA COLLECTED
  - A. Blacks Voting in the South 1947-1948
    - Alabama 1947 (Box-folder 50:1407)
    - Arkansas 1947-1948 (Box-folder 50:1408)
    - Florida 1947 (Box-folder 50:1409)
    - Florida 1948 (Box-folder 50:1410)
    - North Carolina 1947-1948 (Box-folder 50:1411)
    - South Carolina 1947-1948 (Box-folder 50:1412)
    - Georgia 1947-1948 (Box-folder 50:1413)
    - Oklahoma 1948 (Box-folder 50:1414)
    - Tennessee 1948 (Box-folder 50:1415)
  - B. The Butler Papers 1813-1888
    - Marriage License 1813 (Box-folder 51:1416)
    - Tax 1814-15 (Box-folder 51:1417)
    - Tax 1817 (Box-folder 51:1418)
    - Receipt 1817 (Box-folder 51:1419)
    - Tax: Land n.d. (Box-folder 51:1420)
    - I.D. Papers 1824 (Box-folder 51:1421)
    - I.D. Papers 1824 (Box-folder 51:1422)
    - Tax: Land 1829 (Box-folder 51:1423)
    - Tax: Land 1832 (Box-folder 51:1424)
    - Tax: Land 1833 (Box-folder 51:1425)
    - The Butler Papers: Tax: Land 1834 (Box-folder 51:1426)
    - The Butler Papers: Tax: Land 1835 (Box-folder 51:1427)
    - Tax: Land 1836 (Box-folder 51:1428)
    - Tax: Land 1838 (Box-folder 51:1429)
    - Tax: Land 1839 (Box-folder 51:1430)
    - Tax: Land 1840 (Box-folder 51:1431)
    - Tax: Land 1841 (Box-folder 51:1432)
    - Tax: Land 1842 (Box-folder 51:1433)
    - Tax: Land 1843 (Box-folder 51:1434)
    - Tax 1844 (Box-folder 51:1435)
    - Tax: Land 1845 (Box-folder 51:1436)
    - Tax: Land 1847-48 (Box-folder 51:1437)
    - Tax: Land 1849 (Box-folder 51:1438)
    - Tax: State 1860-61 (Box-folder 51:1439)
    - Tax: State & City 1862 (Box-folder 51:1440)
    - Tax: Land 1850-51 (Box-folder 51:1441)
    - Tax: City 1852-53 (Box-folder 51:1442)
    - Tax: State 1854 (Box-folder 51:1443)
    - Tax: City 1855 (Box-folder 51:1444)
    - Tax: City 1855 (Box-folder 51:1445)
    - Tax: State & City 1856-57 (Box-folder 51:1446)
    - Tax: State & City 1858 (Box-folder 51:1447)
    - Tax: State & City 1859 (Box-folder 51:1448)
    - Tax: State & City 1863 (Box-folder 51:1449)
    - Tax: City 1865 (Box-folder 51:1450)
    - Tax: Federal & State 1866 (Box-folder 51:1451)
    - Tax: State & City 1868 (Box-folder 51:1452)
    - Tax: State & City 1870, 1871 (Box-folder 51:1453)
    - Tax: City 1877 (Box-folder 51:1454)
    - Tax: State 1877 (Box-folder 51:1455)
    - Tax: City 1878 (Box-folder 51:1456)
    - Tax: State 1878 (Box-folder 51:1457)
    - Tax: City 1879 (Box-folder 51:1458)
    - Tax: State 1879 (Box-folder 51:1459)
    - Tax: City 1880 (Box-folder 51:1460)
    - Tax: State & City 1881 (Box-folder 51:1461)
    - Tax: City 1886 (Box-folder 51:1462)
    - Tax: State 1882 (Box-folder 51:1463)
    - Tax: City 1883 (Box-folder 51:1464)
    - Tax: State 1884 (Box-folder 51:1465)
    - Tax: City 1884 (Box-folder 51:1466)
    - Tax: City 1885 (Box-folder 51:1467)
    - Tax: State 1888 (Box-folder 51:1468)
    - Miss n.d. (Box-folder 51:1469)
  - C. The Dews Papers 1802-1880
    - The Dews Papers--Land, survey, bills, receipts 1802, 1820, 1823 (Box-folder 52:1470)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts 1827-1828 (Box-folder 52:1471)
    - The Dews Papers: food receipts, grocery list 1829-1836 (Box-folder 52:1472)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, food, silk, ribbons 1837-1838 (Box-folder 52:1473)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, food 1839-1841 (Box-folder 52:1474)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, supplies 1842-1844 (Box-folder 52:1475)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts 1846-1848 (Box-folder 52:1476)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, food, supplies 1848-1850 (Box-folder 52:1477)
    - The Dews Papers: article of agreement 1852-1854 (Box-folder 52:1478)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, trips 1856-1857 (Box-folder 52:1479)
    - The Dews Papers: work agreements, work receipts 1858-1859 (Box-folder 52:1480)
    - The Dews Papers: payment agreements 1860, 1864 (Box-folder 52:1481)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts, food clothes, Tabasco 1866, 1868 (Box-folder 52:1482)
    - The Dews Papers: receipts 1869-1871 (Box-folder 52:1483)
    - The Dews Papers: payments, receipts for land 1874-1877 (Box-folder 52:1484)
    - The Dews Papers: payments for land 1878, 1880 (Box-folder 52:1485)
    - The Dews Papers: payment agreements n.d. (Box-folder 52:1486)
  - D. The Layton Papers 1861-1898
    - The Layton Papers: Tax & Indentured 1864 (Box-folder 53:1487)
    - The Layton Papers: Deed 1866 (Box-folder 53:1488)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & Receipt 1869, 1871 (Box-folder 53:1489)
    - The Layton Papers: Deed 1872 (Box-folder 53:1490)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & Receipt 1873 (Box-folder 53:1491)
    - The Layton Papers: Correspondence 1875-1876 (Box-folder 53:1492)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & City 1877 (Box-folder 53:1493)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State, City & County 1878 (Box-folder 53:1494)
    - The Layton Papers: Receipts 1878 (Box-folder 53:1495)
    - The Layton Papers: Receipts 1879 (Box-folder 53:1496)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & City 1879-1881 (Box-folder 53:1497)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & City 1882 (Box-folder 53:1498)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State & City 1883-1884 (Box-folder 53:1499)
    - The Layton Papers: Correspondence 1888 (Box-folder 53:1500)
    - The Layton Papers: Tax--State 1888 (Box-folder 53:1501)
    - The Layton Papers: Receipts 1892-1893 (Box-folder 53:1502)
    - The Layton Papers: Petersburg Beneficial Assn. 1893 (Box-folder 53:1503)
    - The Layton Papers: Petersburg Beneficial Assn. 1896 (Box-folder 53:1504)
    - The Layton Papers: Teaching Certificate 1876, 1878 (Box-folder 53:1505)
    - The Layton Papers: Teaching Certificate 1884-1888 (Box-folder 53:1506)
    - The Layton Papers: Normal Institute For Teachers 1884 (Box-folder 53:1507)
  - E. The Woodridge Papers 1883-1910
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipt 1883 (Box-folder 54:1508)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Report Card & Indenture 1884, 1889 (Box-folder 54:1509)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1889-1890 (Box-folder 54:1510)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1891 (Box-folder 54:1511)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1892-1893 (Box-folder 54:1512)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1894 (Box-folder 54:1513)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1894 (Box-folder 54:1514)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Tax--County 1895 (Box-folder 54:1515)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1896 (Box-folder 54:1516)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Correspondence 1897 (Box-folder 54:1517)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1897 (Box-folder 54:1518)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1898 (Box-folder 54:1519)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1899 (Box-folder 54:1520)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts--Jordan Baptist Church 1899 (Box-folder 54:1521)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts--Jordan Baptist Church 1899 (Box-folder 54:1522)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts--Jordan Baptist Church 1899 (Box-folder 54:1523)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts 1899 (Box-folder 54:1524)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Tax--County 1899 (Box-folder 54:1525)
    - The Woodridge Papers: Receipts & Correspondence 1901, 1903, 1910 (Box-folder 54:1526)
  - F. By County
    - Appomattox County--State of Virginia Liquor License 1895 (Box-folder 55:1527)
    - Augusta County--Free blacks, identification papers 1843-49 (Box-folder 55:1528)
    - Bedford County--list of working slaves n.d. (Box-folder 55:1529)
    - Buckingham County--survey of a piece of land 1829 (Box-folder 55:1530)
    - Brunswick County-list of free blacks 1860 (Box-folder 55:1531)
    - Campbell County--letter to a son and daughter 1843 (Box-folder 55:1532)
    - Chesterfield County--identification paper for a free black 1819 (Box-folder 55:1533)
    - Dinwiddie County--papers of a free black 1855 (Box-folder 55:1534)
    - Fauquier County--teaching contract 1886 (Box-folder 55:1535)
    - Goochland County--papers of a free black 1827 (Box-folder 55:1536)
    - Halifax County--letters 1806 (Box-folder 55:1537)
    - Henry County--slave records 1865 (Box-folder 55:1538)
    - Isle of Wright County--receipt of goods 1893 (Box-folder 55:1539)
    - Louise County--identification paper 1896 (Box-folder 55:1540)
    - Lunenburg County--trespassing paper 1862 (Box-folder 55:1541)
    - Loudoun County--list of school policies for students 1887 (Box-folder 55:1542)
    - Mecklenburg County--a list of free blacks 1861 (Box-folder 55:1543)
    - Nansemond County--constitution of laws 1894 (Box-folder 56:1544)
    - Nelson County--free Negro certificates n.d. (Box-folder 56:1545)
    - Norfolk County--warrant of arrest, receipts of taxes 1853 (Box-folder 56:1546)
    - Powhatan County--identifications papers 1856 (Box-folder 56:1547)
    - Prince George County--receipt for state tax, land, school tax 1878 (Box-folder 56:1548)
    - Southampton County--papers, certificates of free blacks 1821-1831 (Box-folder 56:1549)
    - Southampton County--papers, certificates of free blacks 1831-1887 (Box-folder 56:1550)
    - Surry County--papers, certificates of free blacks 1846 (Box-folder 56:1551)
    - Sussex County--letters 1777 (Box-folder 56:1552)
    - Unknown--receipts, letter to the church 1862-1867 (Box-folder 56:1553)
  - G. By City
    - Ettrick (Slave Ettrick--permission)--permission n.d. (Box-folder 57:1554)
    - Farmville City-tax receipt of Booker Jackson 1859-1860 (Box-folder 57:1555)
    - Fredericksburg City--Identification paper 1833-1850 (Box-folder 57:1556)
    - Petersburg City--bill/bond 1830 (Box-folder 57:1557)
    - Petersburg City--receipt 1842 (Box-folder 57:1558)
    - Petersburg City--slave court papers 1820-1822 (Box-folder 57:1559)
    - Petersburg City--receipts, identification papers 1854-1855 (Box-folder 57:1560)
    - Petersburg City (Slaves--Patrols)--receipts, newspaper clippings 1836-1876 (Box-folder 57:1561)
    - Petersburg City--letters 1822-1824 (Box-folder 57:1562)
    - Petersburg City--receipts, letters 1865-1866 (Box-folder 57:1563)
    - Petersburg City (Jane Green)--stamped enevelopes, letter 1872 (Box-folder 57:1564)
    - Petersburg City--voting ticket democratic and republican 1888-1890 (Box-folder 57:1565)
    - Williamsburg City--letter 1772 (Box-folder 57:1566)
  - H. Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous n.d. (Box-folder 58:1567)
    - Miscellaneous: Financial Documents n.d. (Box-folder 58:1568)
    - Miscellaneous: Financial Documents n.d. (Box-folder 58:1569)
    - Miscellaneous: Free Papers n.d. (Box-folder 58:1570)
    - Miscellaneous: Free Papers n.d. (Box-folder 58:1571)
    - Miscellaneous: Free Papers n.d. (Box-folder 58:1572)
    - Miscellaneous: Letters n.d. (Box-folder 58:1573)
    - Miscellaneous: Slave Pass n.d. (Box-folder 58:1574)
    - Miscellaneous: Will n.d. (Box-folder 58:1575)
    - Minutes of the Virginia Baptist State Sabbath School Union/Essays 1871 (Box 59)
    - Baptist Principles Booklet 1889 (Box 59)
    - Teachers Guide Bartholomew's Drawing Book Nov 2, 1871 (Box 59)
    - Diary of a Missionary from South Africa 1881-1882 (Box 59)
    - "Intoxicating Liquors" by William Henry Johnson 1902 (Box 59)
    - "Education as we view it," by William Henry Johnson 1902 (Box 59)
    - A pamphlet at the Great Republican Ratification Meeting 1896 (Box 59)
    - A history of the Bethany Baptist Sunday School Convention 1888 (Box 59)
    - Index: Appeal's Annual and Resume of Historical Events 1888 (Box 59)
    - Race and suffrage In the South since 1940, by Luther P. Jackson 1948 (Box 59)
    - Southern Conference on Race Relations 1942 (Box 59)
    - (Box 59)
    - The Hero of Jerusalem 1881-1882 (Box 59)
    - The Negro Protective Association of Virginia 1897 (Box 59)
    - Writing Notes: Historical Points Petersburg n.d. (Box-folder 60:1576)
    - Writing Notes: Petersburg Free blacks n.d. (Box-folder 60:1577)
    - Writing Notes: Petersburg Map n.d. (Box-folder 60:1578)
    - Writing Notes: Colonization Society--Petersburg n.d. (Box-folder 60:1579)
    - Writing Notes: F.N.L.P.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1580)
    - Writing Notes: F.N.L.P.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1581)
    - Writing Notes: F.N.L.P.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1582)
    - Writing Notes: Office Holders n.d. (Box-folder 60:1583)
    - Writing Notes: Colson--Roberts n.d. (Box-folder 60:1584)
    - Writing Notes: Office Holders n.d. (Box-folder 60:1585)
    - Writing Notes: 13--Religions n.d. (Box-folder 60:1586)
    - Writing Notes: V.T.A. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1587)
    - Writing Notes: Petersburg n.d. (Box-folder 60:1588)
    - Writing Notes: F.N.L.P.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1589)
    - Writing Notes: F.N.L.P.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1590)
    - Writing Notes: O.H. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1591)
    - Writing Notes: Charles City n.d. (Box-folder 60:1592)
    - Writing Notes: Nansemond n.d. (Box-folder 60:1593)
    - Writing Notes: Albemarle n.d. (Box-folder 60:1594)
    - Writing Notes: Joseph Ranger Elizabeth n.d. (Box-folder 60:1595)
    - Writing Notes: V.S. & S. in R. n.d. (Box-folder 60:1596)
    - Writing Notes n.d. (Box-folder 60:1597)
    - Ledger: Record Book for the use of Public schools, and scrap book of news-clippings 1875, 1900 (Box 61)
    - Ledger: Samaritan Building Loan and Insurance Association 1892-1900 (Box 61)
    - Notebook: List of property owners 1891-1902 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: County records, slave records 1850-1860 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Lists of land, and occupations lists 1860 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Landowners, property information 1890-1900 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Land and cattle owner 1800-1830 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: List of occupation, color, sex, and age for different cities, counties 1850-1860 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Property papers, living arrangements, land owners etc. 1850, 1860, 1865 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Notes on slave trade, free Negroes, runaway Negroes etc. 1618, 1631, 1662, 1666, 1672, 1716-1800, 1800-1922 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: School papers; bills; attendance 1849-1882 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Papers on Free Negro Ownership of slaves in Virginia July 1841 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Land, property owners n.d. (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Land, property owners 1936 (Box 62)
    - Notebook: Notes, papers of free Negroes, certificates of Freedom 1827-1860 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Land, property papers 1782-1941 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Notes on free Negroes, certificates of freedom 1800-1860 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: School notes, test papers n.d. (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Land, property, occupation papers 1860 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Free Negroes, age, color 1785-1850 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Land, property papers 1870-1902 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: List of slaves, some that are half white 1784-1840 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: Personal Property papers 1851 (Box 63)
    - Notebook: List of free Negroes 1816-1830 (Box 63)
- SERIES VII. MATERIALS WRITTEN BY LUTHER P. JACKSON, SR.
  - A. Feature articles written by Luther Porter Jackson in the (Norfolk, Virginia) Journal and Guide, under the general heading, "Rights and Duties in a Democracy".
    - "Abolishing The Poll Tax" Oct. 8, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1598)
    - "Intricacies of the Poll Tax" Oct. 14, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1598)
    - "Exercising Pressures on Government" Oct. 21, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1598)
    - "Failing To Register" Oct. 29, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1598)
    - "Failing To Embrace Political Opportunities" Nov. 4, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1599)
    - "Failing To Attain Full Fledged Citizenship" Nov. 12, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1599)
    - "Listen America" Nov. 19, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1599)
    - "Not The Bullet But The Ballot" Nov. 26, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1599)
    - (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "Paying The Poll Tax But Failing To Register" Dec. 3, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "Voting In Cities and Countries- A Comparison" Dec. 9, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "The Double Duty Poll Tax" Dec. 15, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "New Year's Eve Resolutions" Dec. 23, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "Good News" Dec. 31, 1942 (Box-folder 64:1600)
    - "Founders Day At The Virginia State College" Jan. 7, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1601)
    - "Voting In the Old Days" Jan. 14, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1601)
    - "Carter Glass Major Prophet" Jan. 21, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1601)
    - "The Newport News Salary Case" Jan. 27, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1601)
    - "Negro History Week" Feb. 4, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1602)
    - "Lincoln, Garrison, and The Negro" Feb. 11, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1602)
    - "The Republican Party and the Negro" Feb. 18, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1602)
    - "The Non-Voting Tradition Among Negroes" Feb. 25, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1602)
    - "The Non- Voting Tradition Among School Teachers" March 4, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1603)
    - "Non-Voting Among College Teachers and Workers" March 11, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1603)
    - "Within the Walls of Segregation" March 18, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1603)
    - "The National Association For The Advancement of Colored People" March 25, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1603)
    - (Box-folder 64:1603)
    - "The Dead Line For School Teachers" April 1, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1604)
    - "The Dead Line For All Citizens" April 8, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1604)
    - "Thomas Jefferson And The Negro" April 15, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1604)
    - "A Ray of Hope For The Future" April 22, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1604)
    - "Negro Suffrage In North Carolina" April 29, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1604)
    - "Arousing A voting Consciousness In The Negro" May 5, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1605)
    - (Box-folder 64:1605)
    - "To The College Graduates of 1943" May 13, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1605)
    - "The Newport News Affair" May 20, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1605)
    - "Abolishing the Poll Tax" May 26, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1605)
    - "Barbering and Scientific Training" June 3, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1606)
    - "Resorting to the Courts" June 8, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1606)
    - "The White Primary" June 17, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1606)
    - "The Spirit of 1881-1883" June 24, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1606)
    - "The New Negro Lawyer" July 1, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1607)
    - "The National Association For The Advisement of Colored People" July 8, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1607)
    - "War and The Negro" July 15, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1607)
    - "The Free Negro In North Carolina" A Review of an Important Book July 22, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1607)
    - "Equalization Of Salaries In North Carolina" July 29, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1607)
    - "The Newport News Court Case" Aug. 3, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1608)
    - "Virginia Negro Soldiers and Seamen In The American Revolution" Aug. 8, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1608)
    - "The Southern Regional Council" Aug. 13, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1608)
    - "The Opportunity To Advance In Mecklenburg County" Aug. 24, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1608)
    - "Advancing In Nottoway County" Sept 1, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1609)
    - "The Southern Regional Council" Sept. 6, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1609)
    - "Registration Day, October 2, 1943" Sept. 15, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1609)
    - "The Shame Of The Race" Sept. 19, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1609)
    - "Struggling In Princess Ann Country" Sept. 27, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1609)
    - "Caesar Tarrant, A Pilot In The American Revolution" Oct. 4, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1610)
    - "The Nickens Family: Fighters on Land and on Sea" Oct. 12, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1610)
    - "The Brown Family of Charles City County, Virginia" Oct. 16, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1610)
    - "Joseph Ranger: Fighting Sea-Dog of the Revolution" Oct. 27, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1610)
    - "William Flora: A Spy for General Lafayette" Nov. 4,1943 (Box-folder 64:1611)
    - "Speech of A. W. Harris, Negro Member of the Virginia Legislature, Feb 14, 1882" Nov. 11, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1611)
    - "Ministers Of the Gospel and The Voting Movement" Nov. 25, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1611)
    - "The Voting Boom In Portsmouth, Virginia" Dec. 1, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1612)
    - "The Southern Regional Council" Dec. 7, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1612)
    - "Motives For Paying the Poll Tax" Dec. 14, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1612)
    - "The Newport News Affair: The Tragedy of 1943" Dec. 23, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1612)
    - "Abolishing Jim Crow On Street Cars and Buses" Dec. 29, 1943 (Box-folder 64:1612)
    - "The Celebration Of The Emancipation Proclamation" Jan. 5, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1613)
    - "No Name ("The Founding of The Virginia State College)" Jan. 13, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1613)
    - "The Petition Drive Of The Virginia Electoral Reform League" Jan. 19, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1613)
    - "Thomas B. Patterson-Farm Leader" Jan. 26, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1613)
    - (Box-folder 64:1614)
    - "A Token For The School Teachers of Virginia" Feb. 3, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1614)
    - "The History of Negro History" Feb. 9, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1614)
    - "The Virginia Senate And Teachers' Salaries" Feb. 14,1944 (Box-folder 64:1614)
    - "Washington, Lincoln, and The Negro Soldier" Feb. 24, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1614)
    - "A Program of Political And Civil Rights" March 2, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1615)
    - "Poll "Taxless" North Carolina" March 9, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1615)
    - "Candidates For City Councils" March 14, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1615)
    - "Delilah C. Jackson and Her Family" March 22, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1615)
    - "Fighting It Out Again In Newport News" March 29, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1615)
    - "School Teachers and The Voting Instructions Handbook" April 5, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1616)
    - "The Upper South, The Lower South, And The Negro Suffrage" April 13, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1616)
    - "The Call To Pay The Poll Tax" April 20, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1616)
    - "Signs of A Better Day For Voting In Virginia" April 27, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1616)
    - "Living In A Fool's Paradise" May 4, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1617)
    - "The United Negro College Fund Campaign" May 11, 1944 (Box-folder 64:1617)